- Hi, I'm Nick Ortiz.
I'm a board certified
disability insurance attorney.
Today I'm here to talk to you about
Prudential Life Insurance Company.
Also known as Prudential Financial,
or Prudential for short.
You're probably here because Prudential
has denied or terminated your benefits
for long term disability
insurance benefits.
Or, LTD benefits for short.
There are several reasons why Prudential
may have denied your claim.
Perhaps the most common is
that they've sent your file
to one of their doctors for a review,
and their doctor basically has concluded
that you can go back to work.
A second reason why they might
have denied your claim is
because they've had your file reviewed
by a vocational expert or a job expert.
And that job expert has concluded
that given the restrictions that they see
in your medical record, or
as defined by their doctor
that you can go back to work.
A third reason why Prudential
may have denied your claim
is because of a change in the
definition of the term disability.
What that means is, that
for the first two years
of your policy they may
pay benefits so long as you
cannot perform the material
duties of your job.
That is your occupation,
your own occupation
or what we call own occ for short.
But after two years, they
typically will broaden
that definition to see
whether you can do any job
or any occupation.
And while Prudential
may have agreed that you
could not perform your own occupation,
they may feel that you can do other work
or any occupation and deny your
case at that two year mark.
Fourth reason why Prudential
might deny your claim
is they say that there's
insufficient medical evidence
to support the claim.
What that may mean is,
you stopped going to the doctors,
so there's no new medical
evidence to support the case.
Or there's been some
improvement in your condition
through the healing process
and they think that based on
that improvement you
could go back to work.
So those are some of the basic reasons
why Prudential denies claims.
But the good news is, that you
do have the right to appeal
their either denial of benefits,
or termination of benefits.
And that's where talking to an experienced
long term disability attorney can help.
I personally have experience
in handling claims
against Prudential and long
term disability insurance claims
and we welcome an
opportunity to speak to you
about what your legal
rights are as against
that insurance company.
So if you'd like to talk
to somebody right away,
then please give us a
call at 850-308-7833.
Otherwise, if you'd like
some additional information,
then I encourage you to
download a digital copy
of a book that I wrote called
The Top 10 Mistakes That Will Destroy Your
Long Term Disability Claim.
You can download a free
copy at www.FreeLTDBook.com
Thanks for listening, we look
forward to speaking with you.